

💌 acdoussan@gmail.com | 🌃 adam.doussan.info | 🖸 acdoussan | 😾 acdoussan | 🛅 acdoussan

"See every day as an opportunity to better yourself."

Summary.

Current Software Development Engineer II at Amazon. Professional experience specializing in frontend and backend design and development (React, Typescript, Javascript, NodeJS, Java) and cloud infrastructure automation (AWS, Cloudformation, CDK, Gitlab CI/CD). Emacs evangelist who feels at home in a Linux terminal. I am interested in ambiguous projects that provide the opportunity to learn and grow. I love to problem solve, and I have a passion for designing and implementing solutions that are highly scalable and fault tolerant.

Work Experience

Amazon - Amazon Transportation Services

Tennessee, USA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER II

Mar. 2021 - Present

- Designed, lead, coordinated, and implemented an annual rate structure change in the UK in 2 months to meet a hard deadline of February 14th. Organized changes to 11 different services, which were released in 18 different deployments to ensure system stability and rollback options. Coordinated these deployments with 4 different teams in 3 different timezones, involving over 10 SDEs and 4 PMs. These changes provided a 6.6% revenue per package increase, unlocked an additional 1.5MM package volume with a projected 4.7MM additional revenue, and also reduced the time to make these changes in the future from 2 months to 2 weeks. (Java, Micro Services, DynamoDB, NoSQL, REST APIs)
- · Designed a solution to migrate our service from lambda compute to AWS Fargate (ECS, Docker). Mentored an intern and guided them to complete the project. Migration reduced time to deploy developmental changes by 50%, and also eliminated cold starts from our application, allowing us to scale horizontally to meet increased traffic.
- Designed and implemented a data conversion and export pipeline to enable business report generation and KPI deep dives. Created a reusable CDK library implementation that is used by 4 different services. (NodeJS, Typescript, AWS CDK, DynamoDB, NoSQL, MySQL, Relational, AWS Lambda, AWS SQS)
- · Coordinated and lead a design patterns book club. Read book with 2 other engineers, and took turns leading a review session for each chapter with an average attendance of 5 people.
- · Mentored 4 coworkers and lead a review meeting following a 6 week training to help them get the cloud practitioner AWS certification.

Amazon - Amazon Transportation Services

Tennessee, USA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Nov. 2019 - Mar. 2021

- · Designed, created mockups, and implemented proof of concept UI that helped sales team negotiate rates with lead shippers, while also enforcing guardrails to protect profit margins. (React, JavaScript, Redux)
- Designed, lead, and implemented system expansion to support negotiations for all shippers, not just leads. Created tasks and estimates, owned delivery timeline, owned communication with stakeholders, and collaborated with coworkers to deliver on time and deprecate an excel based workflow. (Java, Micro Services, DynamoDB, NoSQL, REST APIs)
- Organized multiple Nashville wide programming competitions (dubbed Codefest) with a peak of 27 participants, and an average satisfaction rating of 4.18 out of 5.

Harris Corporation - Radio Frequency Interference Monitoring System

Florida, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2018 - Nov. 2019

- · Interpreted customer requirements and designed class, component, and sequence diagrams to ensure system met customer needs. Defined and linked interfaces to model data and execution flow. (MagicDraw)
- Mocked, designed, and implemented web interface. (React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
- Designed and implemented backend services. (Swagger, Node, Python)
- · Created automated deployment and configuration of services and interfaces. (Ansible, Make, RPMs, NGINX, AWS)

Education

University of Central Florida

Florida, USA

B.S. OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug. 2014 - May. 2018

- Computer Science team lead of UCF's Society of Automotive Engineers (SAE).
- Attended UCF programming team practices weekly.

Certifications

Aug. 2021 Solutions Architect, AWS

Dec. 2020 Cloud Practitioner, AWS



MENTOR

Pivot Technology School Tennessee, USA

Aug. 2021 - Current

• Served as a mentor for one student attending a 16 week accelerated coding bootcamp targeted at closing the gap for minorities in tech.

- Assisted student with questions related to the curriculum, and provided examples on how classroom learning applies in the real world.
- Assisted student with questions related to the curriculum, and provided examples of now classroom learning applies in the rea
 Provided student insights into the world of tech, and provided help with and insight into the interview process.

Eve Profit USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul. 2020 - Current

- Designed and implemented a responsive website that helps Eve Online players find market information for in game items. (React, Typescript, Redux)
- Designed and implemented a login system that allows users to see customized profit and return on investment. (React, Typescript, Redux)
- Designed and implemented an automated image export processor that takes exported icons from the game and uploads them to a CDN so that they can be served on demand on the website. (Typescript, AWS Lambda, AWS Cloudfront)

Home Lab USA

AT HOME IT ADMIN Oct. 2021 - Current

- Dell R210 II running PFSense as my firewall, OS installed on two mirrored SSDs using ZFS, connected to a Dell PowerConnect 7048 switch for VLAN support.
- Dell R720 running Proxmox as a hypervisor. TrueNAS core runs in a VM to manage my storage, with the raid controller (flashed to HBA mode) passed directly through via PCIE passthrough. VM storage made available by NFS running on TrueNAS.
- Highly available Pihole running as both a VM on the R720 and directly on a Raspberry pi, kept in sync with Gravity Sync. Automatic failover handled by a VIP managed by keepalived. DNS queries handled by Unbound, running on the PFSense firewall.
- Other services include HAProxy (load balancer and TLS termination), Suricata (IPS and IDS), Dashy, Home Assistant, Portainer, Plex, and Guacamole.